# Mitchell Nguyen

(504) 451-3936 | mitch01nguyen@gmail.com | Gonzales, LA linkedin.com/in/mitchellnguyen504

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Excelled problem solver with 460+ training hours and experienced Full Stack Java Developer. Interested in attaining a coding career that will enable me to excel in software development and utilize my previous work experience. Eagerly looking forward to employing my communication skills in a team-oriented workspace

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

# **W3Schools JavaScript Certification**

- Java
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Spring Boot
- Spring Data JPA

- Spring Security (JWT)
- Bootstrap
- REST API's
- SQL
- Unit Testing (JUnit, Mocha)
- SOLID OOP Principles
- Dependencies Injection
- Docker
  - Postman
  - Git

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Generation Junior Full Stack Java Developer Program** | Remote | August 2022 – December 2022 *Training Participant* 

- Participated in a 16-week, 460+ hour Junior Full Stack Java Developer program that emphasized hands-on practical application.
- Learned and deployed the technologies involved in creating innovative full stack web applications with Java using Spring Boot Framework, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS.
- Conducted unit scripts test with JUnit and Mocha, and troubleshot and debugged issues to ensure the quality and functionality of the code.
- Collaborated with peers on our e-commerce project, connecting the front-end and back-end driven database using the SCRUM development life cycle.
- Construct Docker container that integrates a Spring Boot application and a MySQL database.

Electronic Arts | Baton Rouge, LA | May 2022 – August 2022

Video Game Quality Assurance Tester

- Ensured station's consoles and computers have the correct build/version.
- Efficiently reported bugs and queries using JIRA.
- Playtest, Task Specifics, and Ad-Hoc for upcoming releases.
- Familiar with bug reporting tools such as video and photo editor, screen recorder, and in-game commands.
- Worked profoundly with small teams for ad-hoc or specific tasks and large-scale teams for playtesting.

Green Heart Meals | Lafayette, LA | June 2020 – May 2022

Cook/Website Manager

- Prepared and cooked meals according to daily inventory of 1000 meals.
- Displayed and sustained adequate inventory of 75% in the store fronts.
- Assisted the redesign of GreenHeartMeals.com with Sprwt, a meal prep software.
- Maintained accurate inventory and updated photos and descriptions on website.
- Ensured user experience across the website is smooth with no bugs.

#### **EDUCATION**

Delgado Community College | New Orleans, LA |

- Associate of Applied Science in Information Technology
- Cumulative GPA: 3.7/4.0 | Dean's List